The American Center of Polish Culture records CPAA.09.04
Connecticut Polish American Archives
The American Center of Polish Culture records
1984-2010
CPAA.09.04
Connecticut Polish American Archives
17.0 Linear feet
The American Council for Polish Culture (ACPC) initiated the establishment of the American Center of Polish Culture (ACPC) in Washington, D.C. Since the acronyms of both organizations are the same we refer to the American Center of Polish Culture as the Center. In 1985, during the annual conference of the American Council of Polish Culture (ACPC) it was decided that a Polish Center has to be established in the US capitol and an initial fundraising campaign had started. In 1989 the American Center of Polish Culture was incorporated and in 1991 a building was purchased. The Center was established with a significant help and support of the American Council of Polish Culture and individual supporters from the entire country. However with time the donations diminished and the organization didn't have the means to run such an expensive Center. In January of 2010 the National Polish Center, that was the official name of the Center, was acquired by the Kosciuszko Foundation and become the KF’s Washington DC Center. The collection consists of administrative and financial records covering years 1984-2010.
American Center of Polish Culture.
Koproski, Alexander R.
Biographical/Historical note
The American Council for Polish Culture (ACPC) initiated the establishment of the American Center of Polish Culture (ACPC) in Washington, D.C. Since the acronyms of both organizations are the same we refer to the American Center of Polish Culture as the Center. However in the finding aid the Center's abbreviation ACPC is being used. In 1985, during the annual conference of the American Council of Polish Culture (ACPC) and their affiliated clubs, the idea of establishing a presence in the US capitol, in Washington D.C. was discussed. Blanka Rosenstiel, then the President of ACPC and the affiliated clubs fully supported the idea. It was decided that substantial funds have to be collected to purchase a building in Washington that will illuminate Polonia and their contribution to American society. In order to succeed and to build a strong program for such center a fundraising campaign had to be crafted and executed. Patricia and Alexander Koproski, long time Polonia organizers and promoters from Stamford, CT, were called to lead this fundraising effort. The goal was set to rise one million dollars. The Koproskis’ made an initial contribution of $110,000 to the fund and with that started campaigning for funds on the national scale. Polish Americans wanted to establish a presence in the US Capitol to show not only Polonia’s contribution to the world's heritage but also to make an impact on decision making process among politicians and to advocate for Polish causes. Donations and bequests came from across the country, especially from Americans of Polish descent these of second and third generation. In 1989 the American Center of Polish Culture was incorporated in Washington DC with tax-exempt, nonprofit organization status. In 1991 a building was purchased and the center's board of directors elected Dr. Kaya Mirecka-Ploss as the Center's first executive director. Dr. Ploss, then president of the American Council for Polish Culture, took on the monumental task of renovating, decorating, and furnishing the building and to create a long term program for the Center. Members of the board represented all generation of Polonia all of them contributed their skills and expertise on voluntary basis. With time the Center has developed a membership base, which faithfully contributed to the support of the center's programs. Responses for annual appeals were significant in the first decade and the center received not only money but also artwork and furniture and established a significant library. With increased donations and number of programs the day to day operations had increased and the cost of keeping the Center increased as well. More funds were needed for the Center to continue its rich program, which included numerous concerts, exhibitions, lectures, seminars, and educational programs for local schools. The Center hosted a vacation program for children from Poland for a two-week visit to the United States. In September of 2005 Dr. Ploss retired from her position as an executive director, and after her until the dissolution of the Center, in January of 2010, there were several executive directors whose major task was to strengthen the Center's membership base and to develop interesting programs in partnership with other cultural institutions in the area. The Center was established with a significant help and support of the American Council of Polish Culture however the Centers’ Board of Directors decided to be an independent organization. The Center was getting enough donations to be independent and to sustain a large number of donors. However in mid-2000’s it became apparent that without substantial donations or grants the Center will not be able to keep its operations on an existing level. Several actions were taken by the executive board of the Center: a marketing company was hired to develop a long term strategy, highly publicized testimonial dinners were organized, but these efforts did not bring the expected donations. The center continued to publish monthly newsletter The Center Line that included information about programs, board activities and short articles related to Poland’s history and culture, however it was not a scholarly periodical, and the same information could be obtained from other sources. The Center created a positive image of Polish Americans in the State Capitol but donations from members and occasional donors were not enough to sustain its operations. The initial group of supporters from the second and third generation of Polish Americans was diminishing and new members representing young Polonia were not eager to support this organization not because it was not a worthy cause but because they had different ways of celebrating their heritage. Also the initial operations of the Center have grown considerably and the upkeep of the place was increasingly high. The building is very prominent however was never big enough to host a large event, therefore all events organized by the Center had to take place elsewhere and were costly. Every time an event was held elsewhere the Center lost perfect opportunity to showcase their place. The Center program was attractive however Washington DC offered many events were people could go to get information on Poland and Polish Affairs. The Center struggled to finds its niche within Polonia organizations and didn’t make significant effort to attract and include young members. It is difficult to keep organization going based only on testimonial dinners, small exhibits, and concerts for small audiences and to come up with funding to cover all operational expenses. The Center didn’t have endowment to sustain its operations and it didn’t offer scholarships to attract new and younger members and to stay current and relevant with new generation of Polonia. In 2008 the board of directors of the Center was looking for ways to stop the decline of the Center’s membership and they turn to the Kosciuszko Foundation. The KF was founded in 1925 with its headquarters in NYC. The Foundation promotes closer ties between Poland and the United States through educational, scientific and cultural exchanges. It awards up to $1 million annually in fellowships and grants to graduate students, scholars, scientists, professionals, and artists, and promotes Polish culture in America. It was a natural match and the Center board of directors started negotiation with the Kosciuszko Foundation. In January of 2010 the National Polish Center, that was the official name of the Center, was acquired by the Kosciuszko Foundation and become the KF’s Washington DC Center.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of administrative records, which includes correspondence, minutes of meetings, bylaws, programs, membership lists, clippings and photographs. Financial records include fundraising campaigns, donations, bequests, bank statements, list of donors, and related documents and correspondence.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged in two series administrative and financial. Bothe series are in chronological order.
Conditions Governing Access note
The collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The material was donated by Mr. Alexander Koprowski who was a long time board member of the American Center for Polish Culture.
Accruals note
The material was donated in two installments first part in 2009 and in 2010.
Related Archival Materials note
For related material please go to: American Council for Polish Culture Collection, 1940-2001 CPAA 96-03.
American Center of Polish Culture.; The American Council for Polish Culture.; The National Polish Center.; Administrative records.; Correspondence.; Interviews; Minutes.; Pamphlets.; Photographs; Polish Americans -- History.; Polish Americans -- Societies, etc.; Polish people -- United States; Polish people -- United States -- Intellectual life
- Administrative
  - ACPCC- Constitution and By-laws, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ACPCO- American Council of Polish Cultural Organizations- Manual, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ACPCC- Correspondence- Donations, General, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ACPCC- Convention & Board Meetings, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ACPCC- Polish/American newspapers & publicity, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ACPCC- Correspondence- Donations, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ACPCC- Correspondence- General, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ACPCC- Correspondence- Fundraising letters to priests, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC- Washington in '86 fundraiser, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Wladziu Liberace- Appeal letter, newspaper/magazine articles, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ACPCC- Board Meetings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ACPCC- Convention, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ACPCC- Washington Project- First Raffle- Permit, correspondence, donations, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ACPCC- "Bid for Culture Auction" fundraiser, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - ACPCC- Board Meetings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ACPCC- Washington Project- Correspondence- Donations, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ACPCC- Correspondence- General, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ACPCC- Convention, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ACPC- Incorporation process, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ACPCC- Washington Project- Correspondence- Donations/Fundraising, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ACPCC- Washington Project- Correspondence- Donations/Fundraising Part 2, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - ACPCC- Correspondence- General, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ACPCC- Board Meetings, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ACPCC- Convention, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ACPCC- Convention- Election of Officers, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, donations, fundraisers, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - ACPC- Convention, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - ACPC- Acquiring a building in Washington DC, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - ACPC- Collaboration with The Catholic University of America, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, Donations, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - ACPC- Board Members, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - ACPC- Mission Statement (revised), Amendment of by-laws, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings- Pultusk, Poland, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Executive Director, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ACPC- Fundraising, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ACPC- Convention, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - ACPC- Establishment of sister city program between Pultusk, Poland and New Britain, Connecticut, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ACPC- Opening of the headquarters on "O" Street, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - ACPC- Tenants, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Executive Director, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Koproski's personal, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - ACPC- Center Dedication, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - ACPC- Board Members, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - ACPC- Convention, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - ACPC- Fundraising, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - ACPC- By-law Amendments, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - ACPC- Programs, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - ACPC- "Computers for Poland" Project, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - ACPC- Board Members, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Executive Director, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - ACPC- Grant Writer Position- Announcement, Applicants, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - ACPC- Polonia Activists List, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - ACPC- Programs, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - ACPC- Council Board Meetings & Convention, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - ACPC- Raffle, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - ACPC- Donor Wall, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - ACPC- Binder of founding documents- By-laws, Mission, First board meetings, budget, and reports, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - ACPC- Programs, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ACPC- Trip to Poland- "Honoring Tadeusz Kosciuszko", 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - ACPC- Stock Donations, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ACPC- Council Board Meetings & Convention, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - ACPC- Fundraising, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ACPC- Grant Applications, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - ACPC- Affiliates, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - ACPC- 5 Year Plan, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings/ Committee Meetings, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - ACPC- Disabled Artists of Krakow Program, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - ACPC- Trees for Poland Project, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - ACPC- Programs, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - ACPC- Fundraising, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - ACPC- Polish-American Friendship Festival, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - ACPC- Amber Gallery Dedication, June 10, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - ACPC- Polish Heritage Tour, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - ACPC- Council Meetings, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - ACPC- Council Convention, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - ACPC- Council Meetings & Convention, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ACPC- By-law Ammendments, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ACPC- Development Director Position, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - ACPC- Programs, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - ACPC- Brochure, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - ACPC- Trees For Life incorporation, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - ACPC- Polish Cultural Center trade name change, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - ACPC- Polonaise Music Festival, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - ACPC- Fundraising, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - ACPC- Andrzej Jarecki Scholarship, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - ACPC- Website development, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - ACPC- Programs, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - ACPC- Fundraising, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - ACPC- Employee- Theresa Wilk, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - ACPC- Land Donation- Dr. Ed Genderski, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - ACPC- Council Meetings & Convention, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - ACPC-Correspondence- Donations, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - ACPC-Correspondence- Donations 2, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ACPC- "A Dinner of Celebration"- Poland into NATO, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - ACPC- Poland joins NATO- Articles, reactions, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - ACPC- Programs, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - ACPC- By-law Revisions, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - ACPC- Building Repairs- Roof, basement, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - ACPC- Council Convention- 50th Anniversary, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - ACPC- "A Dinner of Celebration"- First Lady of Poland, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - ACPC- Programs, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - ACPC- Board- Leadership Council, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - ACPC- Council- Correspondence, publicity, relations with Center, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - ACPC- Programs, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - ACPC- "A Dinner of Celebration"- Solidarity, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - ACPC- Programs- Orphans trip to America, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - ACPC- Karski Award, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - ACPC- Building- Insurance coverage, renovations, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - ACPC- Council Meetings & Convention, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ACPC- Programs, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ACPC- Polish Congressman Dedication Dinner, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - ACPC- Employee changes- Magda Szpyrko, Development Director search, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - ACPC- Artists at the Center, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - ACPC- "West Meets East: Art in Poland" Exhibit, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - ACPC- Karski Scholarship & Work with Diverse Demensions, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - ACPC- Programs, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - ACPC- By-law Revisions, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - ACPC- Council Meetings & Convention, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - ACPC- Programs, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - ACPC- Council Meetings & Convention, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - ACPC- Programs, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - ACPC- Member's Survey (Some examples, not all), 2004 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - ACPC- Building- Insurance coverage, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - ACPC- Jan Karski Bequest, 2002-2004 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - ACPC- Programs, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - ACPC- Programs- Founder's Dinner, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - ACPC- Employee Changes/Termination- Anna Darewicz, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - ACPC- Search for new Executive Director, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Proposed Name Change, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - ACPC- Karski Award, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - ACPC- Jan Karski Bequest, 2004-2007 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - ACPC- Council- Convention, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director 2, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - ACPC- Programs, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - ACPC- Programs- Award's Dinner, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - ACPC- Estate/Inheritance Donations, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- General, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - ACPC- Employee Changes/Termination- Monika Krol, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - ACPC- Search for new Executive Director, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - ACPC- New Executive Director- Barbara Kapusto, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - ACPC- Programs, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - ACPC- Publicity, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings- Strategic Planning Retreat, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - ACPC- Building- Apartment for rent, repairs, 2008-2009 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - ACPC- Board Meetings, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Donations, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - ACPC- New Executive Director- Patricia Whitehall-Hill, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - ACPC- By-law revisions, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - ACPC- Correspondence- Board Members & Executive Director, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - ACPC- Donation of posters collection to other institutions, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - ACPC- Programs at the Center, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Albin Obal passing, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - ACPC- Acquisition of National Polish Center (Formerly ACPC) by Kosciuszko Foundation, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 29)